Hello everyone and welcome to
English POD, my name is Marco.
My name is Catherine
and today we're talking
about a dream home, so
building the home of your dreams.
That's right and this
lesson today is advanced,
so it might be a little
bit hard and we're
going to be taking a
look at not only some
vocabulary related to
your home or decorations
and stuff, but also how to treat your loved
one in a nice way, or a little what we call
them, nicknames, cute
names, pet names, pet names.
That's right.
Okay, so stay tuned
we'll be talking about
very specific things
having to do with building
a home and home
remodeling and so we'll hear
this with dialogue one
time, but when we're
back in just a minute here we'll be
talking about what those things mean.
Mr. and Mrs.
Robinson, let's get straight to it.
We have saved up your money for years
and are now ready to build your dream home.
What did you have in mind?
A suburban bungalow
straight out of the 60s.
A perfect lawn with
minimal landscaping, a brick
patio in the backyard
with an old-fashioned
grill, quaint lawn furniture,
and a swimming pool.
A two-car carport,
pastel siding and a gable
roof, completed with white
shutters and a white picket fence.
Uh, honey?
In the living room we would
have moss-green rugs and a
fireplace with a stone mantle
and wood paneling on the walls.
In the kitchen the
cupboards would be a pale
yellow and we would have a
turquoise metal oven, and vinyl flooring.
Um, sweetie, but I was
thinking of more modern
style house, an open concept house
or glass, wood, metal, and concrete.
But sweetums, there's always a lot of
wasted space in those kinds of homes.
Besides, it's just a fad, it doesn't have
the homey feeling the old homes do.
Sweetie Pie, it's not
a lot of wasted space.
It is relaxing and the
house would be eco-friendly
with an in-floor heating
system and designed
to retain the heat of the sun in the winter,
and keep the house cool in the summer.
We would have solar panels on the roof.
Do you know how much those things cost?
What about your vintage furniture, dearest,
and instead of a lawn, which is also a lot
of wasted space, and would require
environmentally harmful pesticides.
We would have a fish
pond in the backyard
and a garden that would cover the
whole yard so we could grow our own food.
But buttercup, I thought
you always said that
you love visiting your
grandmother's house.
And I thought you,
Mr. Scientist, were all up
on saving the planet with your
technological advancements.
Well, I am just going to get some
coffee while you two keep discussing.
Alright, we're back.
So apparently the couple
can't seem to agree.
He wants something
different than what she
does, and in the end I think they were
a little bit irritated with each other.
Doesn't this always happen, though?
I mean, my dream home is
probably not your dream home.
I don't know, it's weird,
but I mean, you would
probably have to, I don't
know, compensate somehow or.
..
Well, that's the beauty of compromising.
You can go back and
forth, but with your loved
one or your spouse,
you have to make some
decisions about what you
want and what they want.
All you need to do
is give a guy his own
room in which he can decorate
and do whatever he wants with it.
That's all you need.
No, no, just any guy, you want to decorate
the house in any way you want to find, but
just give us one room,
you know, like five
meters by five meters where
we can put anything we want.
A beer cooler, a TV, a PS3, a
sun system, and a couple guitars.
Yeah, probably, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, that's not.
You describe it.
I've been to your house like this.
Anyway, we've got a lot of
great words here in language
take away, so let's take
a peak at some of those.
Language take away.
All right, so the first
word that we have, or
it's actually a concept,
minimal landscaping.
Okay, so minimal
is a style minimalist,
actually, and minimal
landscaping is this kind of
style of, well, designing
your lawn or your garden.
Okay.
So minimal means not having
adornments or decorations.
Okay.
So it's kind of like the
less is more type thing.
Exactly.
So minimal architecture
could be very simple,
lots of clean lines,
not much decoration.
It's the opposite of something
that's broke and highly ornamented.
Yeah, and I don't like that.
I'm interested in minimal.
All right, minimalist.
Anyways, we have
minimal landscaping, and
boy, talking about his
patio, an old-fashioned
grill, and he said
quaint lawn furniture.
And it is sometimes, well,
it's usually kind of a bad thing.
We say something is quaint in the way of
saying that it's cute, but we don't really
like it because it's maybe old-fashioned
or, you know, kind of old-style.
So oh, isn't that quaint?
It's something that
people from the city often
say about people in the
country, at least in America.
Oh, because, you know, I went to school
in the East Coast and I'm from the Midwest.
So people in the East
Coast would say, oh,
your house is so quaint,
you know, small and
cute and old-fashioned
because they live in
a big, fancy New York
apartment or whatever.
So quaint is usually something
that's not the nicest, but...
So he's looking for
some lawn furniture
that's not like plastic or new, it's more
like old-fashioned, maybe wood, right?
Right, and kind of traditional
and not fancy, kind of simple.
Now he's also talking about
the house and he wants, well,
a two-carb carport, pastel
siding, and a gable roof.
So now we know what a roof
is, but what is a gable roof?
A gable is a thing, right?
And it's almost like an extension
of the roof in certain parts.
For example, on a
traditional Cape Cod-style
house, you have
windows in the front that
they're not a part of the roof,
they're an extension, they come out.
They're kind of like shopping out like ice.
Exactly, they're coming
out like ice and so the roof,
obviously, you need a roof
on top of those windows.
So that kind of roof, that little
extension that's called a gable.
Okay.
And so there's a wonderful
book that's famous in
American history called
The House of Seven Gables.
That means that on
this roof of the house,
there are seven different
parts that come out.
Seven gables.
It's very unique.
Those houses usually
look a little bit scary.
They do Victorian imposing.
All right, so you have a gable roof.
Now you have shutters
and a white picket fence.
This is typical.
Everyone talks about a white
picket fence around their house.
That's right.
There was even a TV show in
America years ago called Picket Fences.
And I think a picket fence is kind of this
ideal in American culture about having your
own home in the suburbs
and having your own space.
And so around your yard, around your
garden, you have this white picket fence.
And so Picket is I
think the pointed parts,
so a picket fence is
thin pieces of wood that
stand in the ground
and are connected to
protect your property from
other people coming inside.
Okay.
So that's a white picket fence.
You'll hear it all the
time, usually in movies
or in TV shows they
talk about having their
own little house with their
dog and a white picket fence.
Exactly.
Two kids, two cars.
And a white picket fence.
All right.
So now the woman argued that she
wanted something a little bit more modern.
And well, the guy said, you know
what, that's, it's just weights its base.
And those types of homes are just a fad.
A fad.
So a fad is something that is passing.
It's something that's popular for
a short time, but then it goes away.
It's not popular anymore.
Right.
So for example, I think
for a while, remember
those shoes, they used to have little
bread lights in the back and the heel.
Oh, yeah.
And the lights.
Those were a fad.
It was really popular for like a year.
Everyone had them.
Everyone wore them.
And they just went away.
One of my favorite fads of
the 1980s were those shirts that
would change color if the
room temperature changed color.
So if you go outside and it's hot,
they would become bright pink.
But if you're in a cold room,
they would go blue and green.
It was really fun, but they're
definitely out of fashion.
Yeah.
I don't think they were them anymore.
So that's a fad, something that's
temporary, it's popular for a while.
So he called her house
a fad and she says,
well, what about your house,
all this vintage furniture?
What's vintage?
Vintage?
Well, some people
think that vintage is a fad.
A lot of people really enjoy buying
vintage furniture or vintage clothing.
Vintage means old.
Old.
It's a nice way of saying old or
like a nice or cool way of saying old.
Yeah.
Almost like, for example, right now,
1940s and 50s, clothes are very popular.
Loc, girls are into this kind of style.
So it's called, you know, vintage clothing
because it's not from today's style.
Right.
So it's an old style.
Or you could even
call, you know, those big
flowing dresses from the
1970s, vintage clothing.
So vintage furniture
would be furniture that
comes from a different
time, a different era.
But it's popular now.
Right.
Or people like to buy them now.
That's right.
So they're special because
they come from a different time.
Okay.
So those are the words that we
have for today on language takeaway.
Why don't we move on
now to some pet names or
some sweet ways that you can call
your loved ones on fluency builder?
Fluency builder.
So the reason this
dialogue is very funny is
because we have these
two people who are clearly
in disagreement about the kinds
of furniture and houses they want.
But they're, they're being
so nice to each other.
They have these cute names for each other.
So it's really, I don't know.
It's really funny.
It almost seems like they're newlyweds.
But apparently they've been
saving up their entire life.
So maybe they're just one
of those really loving couples.
Oh, sweet arms, sweetie pie, cutie.
All right.
So that's the first one,
sweetums, sweetums.
So obviously the main part of this
board is sweet, sweetum, sweetums.
This is a way to say
hey, sweetie, sweetums.
Sweetums.
So you can say sweetie or sweetums.
Exactly.
And that's, that's a nice way of saying
something or you can go sweetie pie.
Sweetie pie, so pie is a food,
you know, it's like pie is a food.
It's the sweet.
Sweetie pie, because they
honey pie, honey pie, sweetie pie.
So these are all cute.
And you know, the nice
thing about these kind
of pet names, these cute names,
is you can change them if you want.
And they're yours, so
you could say honey
pie, sugar bun, you
know, but they're silly,
but there's no real rule, but these are the
most common, sweetums and sweetie pie.
Okay.
Now moving on to
something a little bit maybe
more formal, dearest, dearest, this makes
me think of my grandparents, dearest.
So dearest comes
from deer, dearest is the
most dear, so someone who's
the most important to you.
So you could say mummy,
dearest, mother, dearest.
Oh, really?
You heard that?
Oh, yeah.
Do people call that their
mother's like mother, dearest?
Mother, dearest.
That's very 19, 30.
So arrogant.
It is.
It's an old time thing.
It's not, we do not say
this anymore, but you
can say, you know, a dearest,
would you mind moving the car?
I like the accent, but
kind of like, English,
all right, and the
last one, buttercup.
This is really popular.
This is really popular and
you've heard this in a song before.
You want to sing the song?
No, usually the song.
Why do you want?
♪ Do you fill me up, buttercup, baby ♪
Okay, so that was in a lot of movies.
The word is buttercup.
Buttercup.
Also in the movie, the princess bride
was the character princess buttercup.
And so this is a sweet, you
know, obviously a sweet thing.
I think a buttercup is a flower.
Really?
Yeah, and so these are
all words you can use.
Names you could use with men and
women, but buttercup is mostly women.
I think the other ones
are more, more general.
But do you think like, do guys say to
their loved ones like Sweden, sweetie pie?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
All right, so I guess
guys, if you want to
be really sweet and
you want to win over the
hearts of the ladies, you can
use these, these words as well.
Another popular one is babe.
Babe.
More of a young person thing to say.
Yeah, I think it's more modern as well.
Babe.
Honey or babe.
Baby.
You're merging on not so not so sweet.
Yeah, but like, hey, baby, how are you?
It's like, nice.
It's like, not like, hey, baby.
All right.
Well, we're going to leave you with
that thought and go listen to this dialogue
one more time, but we'll
be back in a moment.
Mr. and Mrs.
Robinson, let's get straight to it.
You have saved up your money for years
and are now ready to build your dream home.
What did you have in mind?
A suburban bungalow
straight out of the 60s.
A perfect lawn with
minimal landscaping, a brick
patio in the backyard with an old-fashioned
grill, quaint lawn furniture, a swimming
pool, a two-car car
port, pastel siding and a
gable roof, completed with white
shutters and a white picket fence.
Uh, honey?
In the living room, we would
have moss green rugs in a
fireplace with a stone mantle
and wood paneling on the walls.
In the kitchen, the
cupboards would be a pale
yellow and we would have a
turquoise middle oven and vinyl flooring.
Um, sweetie, but I was
thinking of more modern
style house, an open concept house
or glass, wood, metal and concrete.
But sweet homes, there's always a lot
of wasted space in those kinds of homes.
Besides, it's just a fad.
It doesn't have the homey
feeling the old homes do.
Sweetie Pie, it's not
a lot of wasted space.
It is relaxing and the
house would be eco-friendly
with an in-floor heating
system and designed
to retain the heat of the sun in the winter
and keep the house cool in the summer.
We would have solar panels on the roof.
Do you know how much those things cost?
What about your vintage furniture, dearest?
And instead of a lawn,
which is also a lot of
wasted space and would
require environmentally
harmful pesticides, we
would have a fish pond
in the backyard and a
garden that would cover
the whole yard so we
could grow our own food.
At Buttercup, I thought
you always said that
you love visiting your
grandmother's house.
And I thought you,
Mr. Scientist, were all up
and saving the planet with
your technological advancements.
Um, well, I am just going to get some
coffee while you two keep discussing.
Alright, we're back.
So um, apart from
this, uh, decorations and
stuff, are you, do you
agree with the vintage
home, the more like
a minimalist thing, or
do you like the open
concept one, the bigger one?
I, I love the look of minimalism, but as a
place to live, it's not comfortable, right?
And so when I think
of an aesthetic that I
like, you know, a look
that I like, I, I really
like kind of dark
wood, velvety, natural
century, kind of like I think of
old Vienna, you like Castle Dracula?
I like things to be
open, um, and I like a lot
of natural light, but
I also like oversized
kind of heavy furniture and really
luscious, um, fabrics and things like that.
So that's my, I'm actually completely
different because I do like this open concept.
I like those houses
that I like the way they
look inside as well as
outside when they're
kind of squared, big
windows, clean lines, um,
inside is like, for
example, in the kitchen
you have polished
aluminum or polished steel
furniture in the kitchen,
um, as well as, uh,
a lot of white and
red or black, especially,
um, I kind of like that
kind of open spaces.
Yeah.
Primary colors.
Flat screen TVs on the
wall and stuff like that.
Like remote control.
IKEA lamps.
Yeah.
You know, like those
remote controls where
you can, um, open your curtains, your
TV and the lights all at the same time.
I kind of like that stuff.
Cool.
Well, let us know what
you guys like because
everyone has their own
opinion on my beautiful houses.
And if you have any pictures, feel free
to share them with us on our website.
EnglishPod.com.
All right.
We'll see you guys there.
Bye.